Muhammad Qasim

Software Engineer

My enthusiasm for inventing, creating, and optimizing software systems drives me as a software engineer. With a solid theoretical foundation and expertise in Python Django, and Software Quality Assurance, I'm excited to play a key part in developing creative solutions that push the envelope in the industry.

mqasimbhati94@gmail.com

Sialkot, Pakistan

@Qasimbhatti94

03016140577

in linkedin.com/in/Muhammad Qasim

github.com/Mqasim94

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering

Khwaja Fareed University of Engineering and Information Technology (KFUEIT)

10/2019 - 07/2023 CGPA: 3.21/4.00 (80.25%)

Intermediate FSC (Pre-Engineering)

Punjab Group of Colleges

08/2017 - 08/2019 Score-55.6%

Matriculation (Science Group)

The Sigma Foundation High School

06/2015 - 07/2017 Score-64.7%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Python Django Trainee

Knowledge Streams

11/2023 - Present

Volunteer Teaching Assistant

Khwaja Fareed University of Engineering and Information Technology

09/2022 - 07/2023

Achievements/Tasks

 During this time, I assisted the lecturer from the Institute of Computer & Software Engineering. It consists of studyrelated activities.

Navttc Trainer

Khwaja Fareed University of Engineering and Information Technology

05/2023 - 09/2023

Achievements/Tasks

 The NAVTTC employed me as a teaching assistant for the short course "Artificial Intelligence & Robotics".

Internee

NGS Technologies

07/2022 - 08/2022

Achievements/Tasks

 As an intern, I was given the opportunity to work as a frontend WEB developer. I have worked on different programming languages (i.e HTML, CSS, JS) with developers team.

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

KFUEIT Smart Assistant (09/2022 - 06/2023)

• A Role-Based AI chatbot related to admission queries. (FYP)

Material Calculator (01/2020)

 To find the "Cost" and "Material Quantity" of concrete work. This project is in C++.

CRC, Hamming, Parity checker (05/2022)

• Semester Project to check CRC, Hamming and Parity in C++

AFFILIATIONS & CERTIFICATES

ACM-Association for Computing Machinery (06/2022 - 06/2023)

Shield of Appreciation-ACM Chapter KFUEIT (02/2023)

Career Counseling Session By G-Tech Solutions

Certificate of Achivement-ACM Chapter KFUEIT (02/2023)

Workshop on Digital Marketing 4.0

Certificate of Participation-ACM Chapter KFUEIT (05/2022)

Workshop on Amazon FBA Private Label

Certificate of Participation-ACM Chapter KFUEIT (12/2021)

ACM coding Hour event at KFUEIT

LANGUAGES

Puniabi Urdu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English Hindi

Professional Working Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Comparing Event Organizer Teaching

Sports (Tug of war, Kabaddi) Community Welfare